Register of the John M. Levinson Papers, 1954-1991
Hoover Institution Archives
- SUBJECT FILE, 1954-1985
  - Medical Assistance to Southeast Asia
    - General
      - Printed Matter. Includes articles published in medical journals
        - 1968-1969. Includes a typescript of "Medicine and Education at the Danang Medical Center," by J. A. Jackson (Folder 11)
        - 1971-1974 (Folder 12)
        - 1980. "Practicing Medicine on the Edge of Purgatory," Journal of the American Medical Association, September 12. Printed copy (Box 28, Folder 1)
        - 1982. Health Care in Southeast Asia. Printed copy (Folder 2)
        - 1987. "Soft Tissue Sarcoma," JNCI, October. Printed copy (Folder 3)
      - Reports
        - Reynolds, Michael D., "Internal Medicine in a Viet-Namese Province Hospital," n.d. (Box 11, Folder 13)
        - Amberg, Ray M. and Dr. N. L. Gault, Jr., "Observations and Comments on the 'Expansion of Medical Facilities' as Programmed Through the Faculty of Medicine, the University of Saigon, Republic of South Vietnam," 1964 (Folder 14)
        - "Saigon," 1964. Typewritten copy (Box 28, Folder 4)
        - "South Vietnam," 1966. Typewritten copy (Folder 5)
        - "Report of the Viet Nam Medical Appraisal Team," 1967 (Box 11, Folder 15)
        - "Annual Report, Chan-Y-Vien Tin-Lanh and Related Projects," 1968 (Folder 16)
        - "Civilian Health Program," 1968 (Folder 17)
        - "Civilian Health Program," 1968 (Box 12, Folder 1-5)
        - "Second Report of the Coordinating Committee for Military and Civil Health," 1969 (Folder 6)
        - "Institute of Medicine Council Decries Targeting of Hospitals," 1973. Photocopy (Box 28, Folder 6)
        - "South Vietnam," 1975 March 25-30. Typewritten copy (Folder 7)
        - "Health Service in the Socialist Republic of Vietnam," 1981 (Folder 8)
    - Aid for International Medicine, 1967-1981
      - Correspondence, 1972-1982 (Folder 9)
    - American Friends Service Committee (Box 12, Folder 8)
      - General, 1967-1972. Includes reports on the Quaker Rehabilitation Center, Quang Ngai
      - Correspondence, 1973 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - American Refugee Committee. Includes copies of hand drawn sketches of life in a Cambodian refugee camp, 1980. Photocopies (Folder 11)
    - CARE-MEDICO, 1964-1966. Includes reports on Quang Ngai Provincial Hospital (Box 12, Folder 9)
      - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 28, Folder 12)
      - Printed copy of the history of CARE-MEDICO (Folder 13)
    - Committee for Responsibility, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Da Nang Hospital and Library. Includes correspondence, 1966-1982 (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - Dooley (Thomas A.) Foundation, Inc., 1962-1971 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - North Vietnam. Includes correspondence and a report of Dr. Levinson's 1982 visit, May 6-20 (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - Physicians for Social Responsibility, 1966-1968 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Program for International Education in Gynecology and Obstetrics
      - Kampuchea, 1973-1975 (Folder 13)
      - Laos, 1974-1975. Includes a draft of "Report on Laos - Evaluation of Sites for DEIDS," by David M. French (Folder 14)
      - South Vietnam, 1967-1975 (Folder 15)
    - Project Concern, 1965-1967 (Folder 16)
    - Shipment of medical books to South Vietnam. Includes correspondence, 1966-1973 (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - Shipment of medical books to North Vietnam. Includes correspondence, 1974-1985 (Folder 17)
    - Tu Du Nhi Dong Hospital. Includes correspondence in regard to shipment of medication, 1965-1984 (Folder 18)
    - United States. Military Provincial Health Assistance Program, 1967-1969. Includes reports on Public Health Field Program for Phong Dinh and Quang Ngai Provinces (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Volunteer Physicians for Vietnam. Formerly known as Project Vietnam under the U.S. Agency for International Development, 1965-1966 May
      - General, 1965-1972 (Folder 18)
      - Clippings, 1965-1972 (Folder 19)
  - Peace Movement, 1965-1968 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Refugees in Southeast Asia. See also War Victims in Southeast Asia
    - Clippings, 1982 (Box 28, Folder 19)
    - Notes, 1982 (Folder 20)
    - Printed Matter
      - "Refugees in Thailand and Short-Term Medical Aid," Journal of the American Medical Association, 1981 March 31 (Folder 21)
      - "Health Status of Refugees from Vietnam, Laos, and Cambodia," Journal of the American Medical Association, 1982 March 5. Printed copy (Folder 22)
      - "The Refused, the Agony of the Indochina Refugees," Book Digest 1982 May. Printed copy (Folder 23)
    - Reports
      - United States High Commissioner for Refugees Refugee Update - 1982 January (Folder 24)
      - "Summary of Refugee Situation in Thailand," 1982 March 31. Typewritten copy (Folder 25)
    - United States. Congress. Senate. Committee on Human Resources, 1977 September 22 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - United States. Congress. Senate. Committee on the Judiciary
      - Hearings
        - 1978 August 22 (Folder 3)
        - 1979 March 14 (Folder 4)
        - 1979 July 26 (Folder 5)
        - 1979 October 31
      - Reports
        - 1978 March (Folder 6)
        - 1979 July (Folder 7)
        - 1979 August (Folder 8)
    - United States. Congress. Senate. Committee on the Judiciary. Subcommittee on Immigration and Refugee Policy, 1982-1984 (Folder 9)
    - Vietnam Courier, Hanoi, 1979 (Folder 10)
  - Southeast Asia
    - General
      - General, 1965. Includes a report from the U.S. Department of State entitled "The U.S. Stake in Southeast Asia." (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - Maps, 1954-1971 (Folder 2)
      - Notes, 1967 (Box 28, Folder 26)
      - Printed Matter
        - 1964. Remote Areas Development Manual, Community Development Counseling Service, Inc. Printed copy (Box 29, Folder 1)
        - 1965 April. Advisor Handbook for Counterinsurgency, Headquarters, Department of the Army. Printed copy (Folder 2)
        - 1965 June 16. A report for the U.S. Senate Committee on Foreign Relations (Box 14, Folder 3)
        - 1973-1983. Includes booklets published in Hanoi (Folder 4)
        - 1974 August 11. The Asia Magazine, Printed copy (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Du Pont, Pierre S., IV, 1970-1971. Includes a mimeographed position paper with comments by John M. Levinson (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - McCloskey, Paul N., Jr. Statement before the House Committee on Foreign Affairs, Subcommittee on Asian and Pacific Affairs, 1971 June 29 (Folder 6)
    - United States. Senate. Committee on Foreign Relations. Hearings, 1966 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - United States. House of Representatives. Committee on Foreign Affairs. Subcommittee on Asian and Pacific Affairs. Hearings, 1967 (Folder 5)
  - Thailand
    - Clippings, 1980 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Printed Matter. "Focus on Thailand," 1982 March. (Folder 7)
      - Printed copy
    - Reports
      - Dr. Levinson's impressions of Thailand and the medical facilities. Includes interview with Dr. Edward O'Rourke attached to USAID, 1966. Typewritten copy (Folder 8)
      - Dr. Levinson's impressions of the drug abuse in Thailand, 1974 February. Typewritten copy (Folder 9)
  - Vietnam
    - General. Includes population statistics, organization charts, glossaries of military terms, personal accounts
      - Undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
      - 1960-1965 (Folder 8)
      - 1966-1984 (Folder 9)
    - Clippings
      - 1965-1967 (Folder 10)
      - 1968-1973 (Folder 11)
      - 1975 March 30 (Folder 12)
      - 1975 March 31-1978 (Folder 13)
      - 1981-1984 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Maps, 1962-1971 (Folder 2)
    - News Releases, 1972-1975. Includes documentation on the Vietnam agreement announced by the President, 1973 January 23 (Folder 3)
    - Notes, 1983 (Folder 4)
    - Printed Matter
      - General. Includes booklets published in Hanoi and journal articles
        - Undated. Xeroxed copy of the nations needing medical aid, published by World Relief, includes Vietnam (Box 29, Folder 10)
        - Undated. Pocket Guide to Viet-Nam. Printed copy (Folder 11)
        - 1962. Saigon, The American Women's Association Saigon. Printed copy (Folder 12)
        - 1962. U.S. Army Area Handbook for Vietnam, Headquarters, Department of the Army. Printed copy (Folder 13)
        - 1964. Montagnard Tribal Groups of the Republic of Viet-Nam, U.S. Army Special Warfare School. Printed copy (Folder 14)
        - 1965. Country Study Republic of Vietnam, The Department of Defense. Printed copy (Box 30, Folder 1)
        - 1965 (Box 15, Folder 5)
        - 1966 (Folder 6)
        - 1972 (Folder 7)
        - 1978 (Folder 8)
        - 1979 (Folder 9-10)
        - 1980. Includes Reminiscences of a Vietnamese Surgeon by Ton That Tung (Box 16, Folder 1)
        - 1981. Includes the Constitution of the Socialist Republic of Viet Nam (Folder 2-3)
        - 1982 (Folder 4)
        - 1983 (Folder 5)
        - 1987. Garrulax Biology and Conservation in Vietnam Printed copy (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - Hibiscus Series, Hanoi. Vietnamese tales, legends, and stories
        - 1981-1982 (Box 16, Folder 6)
        - 1983-1984 (Folder 7)
      - Vietnamese Experience Series, Hanoi, 1983-1984. Includes topics of education, illiteracy, medicine (Folder 8)
    - Reports
      - General
        - 1962. Includes mimeographed copy of "Notes from the Underground: The Mystique of a Viet Cong" (Box 17, Folder 1)
        - 1965. Report includes statements by President Lyndon B. Johnson, Dean Rusk, and Robert S. McNamara (Folder 2)
        - 1969. Includes mimeographed copy of "Findings on Trip to Vietnam" by the U.S. Study Team on Religious and Political Freedom in Vietnam (Folder 3)
        - 1973 June. Economic and Social Assistance to the Republic of Vietnam, Government of the Republic of Vietnam. Printed copy (Box 30, Folder 3)
        - 1982 (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - Michigan State University. Viet Nam Advisory Group
        - 1961. Reports relate to Vietnamese government administration (Folder 5)
        - 1962 (Folder 6)
      - United States. Department of State, 1962-1974. Includes mimeographed copy of "The Legality of United States Participation in the Defense of Viet Nam" (Folder 7)
    - Speeches (Folder 8)
      - General 1966-1981. Includes a mimeographed copy of "Importance and Need of a Special Statute for Minority Groups in the National Community's Life," delivered by the Minister for Development of Ethnic Minorities, 1969 August 29, and a printed copy of a speech commemorating the fiftieth anniversary of the Vietnamese Communist Party, delivered by Le Duan, 1980 February 2
      - Boyer, William W., "The Agony of Vietnam," 1969 October. Printed copy (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - Vietnamese Foreign Ministry's note addressed to Chinese Foreign Ministry 1982 February 5. Typewritten copy (Folder 5)
  - Vietnam Veterans
    - General
      - General, 1982-1984 (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - Clippings, 1979-1981 (Folder 10)
      - Correspondence, 1982-1985
        - Veterans Administration, 1982-1985 (Box 30, Folder 6)
        - Vietnam Veterans of America, 1983 (Folder 7)
    - Delaware Vietnam Veterans Leadership Program, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Disabled American Veterans (Folder 12)
      - General, 1981?
      - "Post-Traumatic Stress Disorders of the Vietnam Veteran," edited by Tom Williams, Psy.D. 1980. Printed copy (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - War Victims in Southeast Asia. See also Refugees in Southeast Asia
    - General
      - General, 1965-1972. Includes population statistics and a report on refugee resettlement plans (Box 17, Folder 13)
      - Clippings, 1967-1972 (Folder 14)
      - Notes, 1972 (Box 30, Folder 9)
      - Printed matter 1982-1983. Includes article by Ginetta Sagan and material published by Oxfam (Folder 10)
      - Report. Miller, Robert W. and Frank L. Hutchison, "The Vietnam Refugee Program," 1965 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Boat People Project, includes correspondence 1979-1980 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Kennedy, Senator Edward M. Includes statements and speeches issued from the Senator's office
      - 1967-1969 (Box 17, Folder 16)
      - 1970-1972 (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - 1973 (Folder 2)
      - 1974-1978 (Folder 3)
    - Letters to the Editor, 1982. Typewritten copies (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Missing in Action. "On the Question of America's Missing in the Vietnam War," Department of Press and Information, Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Socialist Republic of Viet Nam, 1980. Printed copy (Folder 13)
    - United States. Civil Operations and Rural Development Support (CORDS)
      - General, 1967-1969 (Box 18, Folder 4)
      - Memoranda, 1967. Relates to refugees and civilian war casualties (Folder 5)
      - Reports
        - 1967-1968 (Folder 6)
        - 1969. Includes different drafts of "Assessment of Refugee Program" (Folder 7)
        - 1971. Includes a report on housing, social welfare activities, and the Food for Peace Program in the Vietnamese provinces (Folder 8)
    - United States. Congress. Senate. Committee on the Judiciary. Hearings, 1981 September (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - United States. Congress. Senate. Committee on the Judiciary. Subcommittee to Investigate Problems Connected with Refugees and Escapees
      - General
        - Correspondence, 1971-1975 (Folder 15)
        - Findings and Recommendations, 1968 May 9 (Folder 16)
        - Fragments from the Congressional Record, 1967-1973 (Box 18, Folder 9)
        - Hearings
          - 1967 May 10 and 18; 1967 August 16; 1967 September 21; 1967 October 9, 10, 11, 13, and 16 (Box 30, Folder 17)
          - 1969 June 24 and 25 (Folder 18)
          - 1972 May 8 and 9; 1972 August 16-17 (Box 18, Folder 10)
          - 1972 September 28; 1973 April 16; 1973 August 1 (Folder 11)
          - 1973 May 11 (Box 30, Folder 19)
          - 1973 July 31 (Folder 20)
          - 1974 July 18 (Box 19, Folder 1)
        - Reports
          - 1967 October 11. Statement of Oye V. Stovall, Director, International Division, U.S. General Accounting Office (Folder 2)
          - 1970 September 27 (Folder 3)
          - 1970 September 28; 1970 December 14 (Folder 4)
          - 1972 (exact date unknown); 1972 May 3 (Folder 5)
          - 1974 January 27 (Folder 6)
          - 1975 January 27; 1975 June 9 (Folder 7)
          - 1976 May 17
            - Preliminary mimeographed copy (Folder 8)
            - Printed copy (Folder 9)
      - 1967 Study Mission. Includes itinerary for Senator Edward M. Kennedy (Folder 10)
      - 1968 Study Mission
        - General. Includes typewritten summary of visit by John M. Levinson (Folder 11)
        - Notebook. Includes itineraries, memoranda, typewritten notes, reports (Box 20, Folder 1-4)
      - 1969 Study Mission to South Vietnam. Includes report written by Drs. John M. Levinson and Thomas S. Durant (Folder 5)
      - 1973 Study Mission to North Vietnam
        - General
          - General (Folder 6)
          - Clippings, 1972-1973 (Folder 7)
          - News Releases, Vietnam News Agency, Hanoi, 1973 March 9-16. Includes declarations regarding the Nixon administration, French and English (Folder 8)
          - Printed Matter, 1972 (Folder 9)
          - Reports, 1972 (Folder 10)
        - Itinerary (Folder 11)
        - Notes (Folder 12)
        - Printed Matter (Box 21, Folder 1)
        - Reports (Folder 2)
    - United States. Congressional Records. Proceedings and Debates of the 90th Congress, Second Session 1968 February 6. Printed copy (Box 30, Folder 21)
- POSTAGE STAMPS, 1889-1979
  - Catalogs
    - 1967-1975 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - 1979 (Folder 4)
  - Kampuchea
    - Album (Folder 5)
    - Album pages (Folder 6)
    - Stamps, grouped by subject in envelopes (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Laos
    - Album (Folder 2)
    - Album pages (Folder 3-4)
    - Stamps, grouped by subject in envelopes (Folder 5-6)
  - Southeast Asia - Album. Includes stamps from Kampuchea, Laos, and Vietnam (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Vietnam - Album (Folder 2)
  - Vietnam - Album (Box 24, Folder 1)
- OVERSIZE FILE, 1889-1967
  - Postage Stamps, 1889-1946. Album pages of Indochina stamps (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Printed Matter
    - 1965 (Folder 2)
    - 1966 (Folder 3)
    - 1967 (Folder 4)
  - Scrapbook, 1963 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1966 January-1967 March (Folder 2)
- PHONOTAPE CASSETTE, 1983
  - National Agent Orange Conference Call, Veterans Administration, 1983 November 21 (Cassette-cabinet Cassette Cabinet)
- AUDIO-VISUAL, 1963-1983., (263 prints, 174 negatives, 43 post cards / 14 envelopes; 2 photo albums / 1 album box (Audio-visual 10.A-V, 8M.02)
  Includes photographs and postcards
  - 10 photographs of medical assistance and training given by the Thomas A. Dooley Foundation in Laos., undated (Folder A)
  - 16 post cards of sculptures in the Tay Phuong pagoda, North Vietnam., undated (Folder B)
  - 2 miscellaneous post cards and 20 miscellaneous negatives, including views of canoeing and John M. Levinson., undated (Folder C)
  - 3 photographs and 1 negative of Tu Du Maternity Hospital, Saigon, Vietnam, including view of John M. Levinson., 1963-1975 (Folder D)
  - 2 photographs of Senator Edward M. Kennedy and John M. Levinson during U.S. Senate Committee on the Judiciary, Subcommittee to Investigate Problems Connected with Refugees and Escapees study mission to Vietnam., 1968 (Folder E)
  - 1 photograph, 1 contact sheet, and 36 negatives of John M. Levinson talking to U.S. soldiers during U.S. Senate Committee on the Judiciary, subcommittee to Investigate Problems Connected with Refugees and Escapees study mission to Vietnam., 1969 (Folder F)
  - 25 post cards of artwork depicting Vietnamese military scenes., 1970 (Folder G)
  - 9 photographs of death and destruction caused by bombing in Vietnam., 1972 (Folder H)
  - 29 photographs of U.S. Senate Committee on the Judiciary, Subcommittee to Investigate Problems Connected with Refugees and Escapees study mission to Vietnam, including views of bombed hospitals, war monument, John M. Levinson., 1973 (Folder I)
  - 25 photographs of hospital conditions, surgery, and patients, Cambodia., 1975 (Folder J)
  - 14 photographs and 15 negatives of defoliation, surgery, birth defects during study of Agent Orange in Vietnam., 1982 (Folder K)
  - 100 photographs and 102 negatives of the International Symposium on the Long-Term Ecological and Human Consequences of Chemical Warfare in Vietnam, Ho Chi Minh City, including views of conference, hospital visits, countryside, sightseeing., 1983 (Folder L)
  - 1 negative of Amerasia children, Saigon, Vietnam., 1983 (Folder M)
  - 69 prints depicting mainly hospitals in North and South Vietnam during and after the War., undated (Folder N)
    Includes a print of General Giap.
  - 2 albums of prints depicting hospitals and nursing schools in Vietnam., 1968-1971 (Folder f0)
- Incremental materials (Box 26-30)
  This addition to the collection has not yet been described. Please let the Hoover Institution Archives know if you would like to see this material described.